

Julio César Alonso

Software engineer with more than twenty years experience on IT market, using ruby and other web technologies, in a fast-paced agile software development environment. Gained valuable experience in most phases of the software development life cycle and web environment development. Always strive to provide quality solutions, working in a professional and organized manner, able to meet deadlines and always happy to be part of a team. Furthermore, aim to establish myself in the software industry by improving my technical skills and learning new technologies. In the long run, I would like to architect and lead life-changing projects.

KEY SKILLS	
Programming Languages	Strong Ruby, JavaScript, JQUERY, CSS3, HTML5
Platforms & Frameworks	Ruby on Rails
OS's & IDE's	Mac OS X, Ubuntu, Textmate, Sublime Text
	Eclipse, NetBeans
TDD Techniques	RSpec, Cucumber, FactoryGirl
Web Server	Apache, Nginx, Webrick and Thin
Databases	Oracle, MySQL, Postgre, ReDIS, Riak
Office Suite	Frequent use of the MS Office & OpenOffice suite
Linguistics	Speak English and Spanish as a native.
Other	TDD techniques and best practices.
	Source control systems such as Git.
	Strong knowledge of SEO and google analytics.
	Systems architect and database administrator.
	Ability to manage agile teams and achieve business goals.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

London, UK, 08/2012 - current, Head of development

Joined in 2012 to manage all the development requirements to achieve business goals. Ruby on Rails environment with MySQL as database, RSpec as TDD strategy and Git and GitHub as repositories.

Responsibilities:

- Coordinate Ruby on Rails international development team.
- Design, test and maintenance on the actual platform.
- Develop functional testing protocols and 3rd party integration.
- Build REST API to integrate web platforms with external web and devices.
- Platform administration and tuning.
- Define SEO and analytics strategy for the site.

Madrid, Spain, 06/2006 - 07/2012, Freelance Ruby on Rails Developer

After my experience in ETC, I started to work as freelance on the ruby on rails environment. I have participated from small projects to the biggest startups in Spain. Some of this customers are: Sanitas (BUPA Group), ideas4all.com, buvip.com, Transportes Azkar, Aducex, Gael Lubricantes, Ayuntamiento de Madrid, Oracle España, Cap Gemini

Responsibilities:

- Design, test, development and maintenance on ruby on rails projects.
- SugarCRM implementations on domestic and international implementations.
- Integrate Front&Back office environments
- Work closely with Analysts for the definition of new functionality and provide possible solutions to client issues.
- Write documentation and coding guidelines according to best practices for other developers. Provide suggestions and contribute to the improvement of the framework's architecture.

European Technology Consulting, Madrid, Barcelona SPAIN 06/1998 – 06/2006, Systems and Software Engineer

In 1198 I founded ETC one of the best PeopleSoft technical partners.

Responsibilities:

- Help PeopleSoft to achieve successful projects on the technical side of the projects.
- Installation, upgrade and technical task on PeopleSoft projects.
- Coordinate the consulting team in collaboration with PeopleSoft service manager.

PeopleSoft Ibérica, Madrid, Barcelona SPAIN 10/1996 – 06/1998, Systems and Software Engineer Technical leader at PeopleSoft Spain, subsidiary of PeopleSoft corporation, leader in FDM and HCM software. I participated in domestic and international projects as system engineer.

Responsibilities:

My responsabilities were to ensure successful implementation and design servers architecture. Some
of the customers I worked for was, Sanitas (BUPA group), Transportes Azkar, RaboBank, Visa,
ENUSA, Santander Bank, Banesto Bank, Iberia,

Santander Bank, Madrid, SPAIN 10/1989 – 10/1996, Junior Developer to Manager

My first sex years working on IT was at leader bank in Spain, Santander Bank. Started as junior developer I left it being Manager and leading the web developer team.

Responsibilities:

- Took part in the design, development, maintenance and testing phase of numerous internal projects in Cobol, Cics and DB2.
- New client/server projects in Visual Basic and Visual C++ on the bank environment.
- First home banking in Spain developed on HTML and Oracle database

EDUCATION

Where: 1996-2000 Universidad Politécnica de Madrid.

Title: Bachelor in computers Science

Place: 2001-2004 Know How Business School Modules: Bachelor in Business administration

INTERESTS

Strong interest to all related with new technologies. I have been participated in Spanish and European Ruby on Rails conferences. Continuing improving and reading about new technologies and business. I'm interested in sports and I follow a healthy live style.